Let's discuss the difference between
projects and operations.
So over on the left side of the next
slide, we've got projects.
We'll always produce a unique product,
service, process, result.
Yes, a new or better process is a project.
And I skip that first bullet.
It has a beginning and yes, it's supposed
to have an end.
A project can't run on indefinitely.
So you'll start it and you're supposed to
end it.
It will be if you look at that third
bullet progressively elaborated.
That's a key term you want to understand.
We usually don't know everything up front.
So we'll start a process.
Then we'll move.
We'll uncover some details.
Then we'll do another process.
Uncover some details.
Go back and update what we started.
So again, we don't know everything right
off the bat.
We will uncover new details.
along the way go back and update plans and
documents all right an example of a
project adding new functionality to a
system operations I'm going right to this
second one again is repetitive and ongoing
up one it indoors for the product life
cycle so through our project and beyond
once our project's done operations often
uses that new process it operations is
performed many times or hundreds of times.
All depends on what you're doing.
So an example of operations, ramping up
production due to increased demand.
So you're already producing something.
You're going to produce more, not
something new.
That's the difference.